Guide to the Philippines Army Headquarters Bulletins, 1936-1945
Philippines Army Headquarters Bulletins, 1936-1945
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Philippines Army Headquarters Bulletins, 1936-1945
4405
Philippines Army Headquarters.
1.2 cubic ft.
Bulletins.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Bulletins issued by the Philippines Army Headquarters during World War II, including a set of statements issued by General Douglas MacArthur.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Bulletins issued by the Philippines Army Headquarters during World War II, including a set of statements issued by General Douglas MacArthur.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Philippines. Army. Headquarters.; MacArthur, Douglas, 1880-1964.
Subjects:
World War, 1939-1945--Philippines.
Places:
Philippines--History--1898-1946.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Commonwealth of the Philippines, Army Headquarters, Manila. Bulletins, 1936-1937
Box 1
Series II. Commonwealth of the Philippines, Army Headquarters. Bulletins, 1938-1941. Incomplete
Box 1
Series III. Commonwealth of the Philippines, Army Headquarters, Manila. General Order Bulletins, 1938-1941
Box 1
Series IV. Commonwealth of the Philippines, Army Headquarters, Manila. Training Directives, 1937-1938
Box 1
Series V. Notes prepared for the instruction of Philippine Civil Affairs personnel, 1944-1945
Box 1
Series VI. Standing Operating Procedures, General Headquarters, Southwest Pacific Area, 1944-1945
Box 1
Series VII. Government of the Philippine Islands, Department of the Interior and Labor Headquarters. Philippine Constabulary, Manila, 1933
Box 2
Series VIII. Commonwealth of the Philippines, Army Headquarters, Manila. General Orders, 1936-1937. Incomplete
Box 2
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Commonwealth of the Philippines, Army Headquarters, Manila. Bulletins, 1936-1937
  - Bulletins, 1936; No. 1, 19, 21, 49 & 76. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1937; No. 1-9. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, Mar. 1937; No. 36-42. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, Apr. 1937; No. 43-61. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, May 1937; No. 62-77. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, June 1937; No. 78-90. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, July 1937; No. 92-95, 97, 101-105, 108-110. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bulletins, Aug. 1937; No. 111-127 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bulletins, Sept. 1937; No. 128-142, 144-150. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bulletins, Oct. 1937; No. 151-152, 154-155, 157-171. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bulletins, Nov. 1937; No. 172-193. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bulletins, Dec. 1937; No. 194-199. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bulletins, Dec. 1937; No. 200-209 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series II. Commonwealth of the Philippines, Army Headquarters. Bulletins, 1938-1941. Incomplete
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1938; No. 4-15, 17-21. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bulletins, Feb. 1938; No. 22-20, 31-37. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bulletins, Mar. 1938; No. 38-40, 42-57. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bulletins, Apr. 1938; No. 58-77. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bulletins, May 1938; No. 78-94. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Training Directives, June 1938; No. 30. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bulletins, June 1938; No. 95-100. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bulletins, June 1938; No. 111-126. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Philippine Government Service System., May, June 1938 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bulletins, Aug. 1938; No. 122, 127-135. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bulletins, Aug. 1938; No. 137-140 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bulletins, Sept. 1938; No. 141-146, 148-160. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bulletins, Sept. 1938; No. 161-165. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bulletins, Oct. 1938; No. 166-185. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bulletins, Nov. 1938; No. 189-196, 198-199. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bulletins, Dec. 1938; No. 200, 202-209, 211-213, 216. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bulletins, Jan. 1939; No. 1-6, 8-11 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bulletins, Feb. 1939; No. 12, 13, 16-17. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bulletins, July 1939; No. 97. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bulletins, July 1940; No. 85. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bulletins, Sept. 1940; No. 132. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bulletins, Oct. 1941; No. 136 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Series III. Commonwealth of the Philippines, Army Headquarters, Manila. General Order Bulletins, 1938-1941
  - General Order Bulletins, Jan. 1938; No. 3-18, 20 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - General Order Bulletins, Jan. 1939; No. 1-10, 12-16. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - General Order Bulletins, Oct. 1940; No. 145, 188. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - General Order Bulletins, Aug. 1941; No. 88, 148-151. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - General Order Bulletins, Sept. 1941; No. 160, 162, 177. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - General Order Bulletins, Oct. 1941; No. 181, 183, 185, 188-189. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - General Order Bulletins, Feb. 1938; No. 21-32. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - General Order Bulletins, Mar. 1938; No. 33-43, 45-46. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - General Order Bulletins, Apr. 1938; No. 47-58. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - General Order Bulletins, May 1938; No. 59-71. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - General Order Bulletins, June 1938; No. 72-90. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - General Order Bulletins, July 1938; No. 91-110. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - General Order Bulletins, Aug. 1938; No. 111-128 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - General Order Bulletins, Sept. 1938; No. 129-145 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - General Order Bulletins, Oct. 1938; No. 146-171. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - General Order Bulletins, Nov. 1938; No. 172-174, 176-178, 187-189. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - General Order Bulletins, Dec. 1938; No. 190-207. (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Series IV. Commonwealth of the Philippines, Army Headquarters, Manila. Training Directives, 1937-1938
  - Training Directives, June 1937; No. 8. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Training Directives, Nov. 1937; No. 12-14. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Training Directives, Nov. 1937; No. 12. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Training Directives, Dec. 1937; No. 15-16. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Training Directives, Mar. 1938; No. 17-21. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Training Directives, Apr. 1938; No. 22. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Training Directives, May 1938; No. 23-28. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Training Directives, June 1938; No. 29. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Training Directives, Sept. 1938; No. 31 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Training Directives, Oct. 1938; No. 32 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Training Directives, Dec. 1938; No. 33-39. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Training Directives, Jan. 1939; No. 40 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Training Directives, Feb. 1939; No. 41 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Training Directives, July 1940; No. 70-71. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Training Directives, Oct. 1941; No. 111. (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Series V. Notes prepared for the instruction of Philippine Civil Affairs personnel, 1944-1945
  - Instructional Notes on Philippine Civil Affairs., Oct. 10, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Instructional Notes on Philippine Civil Affairs., Nov. 22, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Instructional Notes on Philippine Civil Affairs., Jan. 13, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Series VI. Standing Operating Procedures, General Headquarters, Southwest Pacific Area, 1944-1945
  - Civil Administration and Relief of the Philippines., October, 1944; Policy of the Commander-in-Chief (Douglas MacArthur). (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Civil Administration and Relief of the Philippines., Nov. 15, 1944; Policy of the Commander-in-Chief (Douglas MacArthur). (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Civil Administration and Relief of the Philippines., Jan. 13, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Proclamations to the people of the Philippines, 1944; by General Douglas MacArthur. (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Series VII. Government of the Philippine Islands, Department of the Interior and Labor Headquarters. Philippine Constabulary, Manila, 1933
  - General Orders, Jan. 1933; No. 3-4. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Series VIII. Commonwealth of the Philippines, Army Headquarters, Manila. General Orders, 1936-1937
  - General Orders, Sept. 1936; No. 95, 98-102, 104-105. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General Orders, Oct. 1936; No. 106, 108-114, 116-124. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - General Orders, Jan. 1937; No. 17-18. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General Orders, Feb. 1937; No. 21-24-25, 29-30, 32, 34-35. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General Orders, Mar. 1937; No. 37-38, 40-45, 48. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General Orders., Apr. 1937; No. 49-65 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - General Orders, May 1937; No. 67-75, 77-82. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - General Orders, June 1937; No. 83-102. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - General Orders, July 1937; No. 103, 105-109, 111-118 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General Orders, Aug. 1937; No. 121, 123-135. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General Orders, Sept. 1937; No. 136-149, 150-152. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - General Orders, Oct. 1937; No. 153-167. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - General Orders, Nov. 1937; No. 169-186. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - General Orders, Dec. 1937; No. 187-192, 195-200. (Box 2, Folder 14)